daniela@dnmpss.com

Daniela Passos

Proactive. Professional. Creative.

Building skills, projects, and a strong portfolio as a Software Developer after a great marketing and social media strategic background by working 7+ years as a Fullstack Marketer across various industries such as Blockchain, DAOs, Filmmaking, Beauty, Fashion, and other practices.

View full Resume and Portfolio here.

Skills

- React, NextJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, and Swift
- Social Content Management and Strategy (Twitter, Youtube, TikTok)
- Content Creation
- Photography and Filmmaking
- Creative writing for Social Media
- Figma, Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Illustrator, InDesign, and Premiere

- Inbound Marketing
- Customer Success
- Facebook Ads
- Google Adwords
- Google Analytics
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Excel

Experience

FEB 2023 - NOW

Developer Relations / Hashnode, San Francisco — United States

Build and nurture a strong community of developers on the platform: This involves engaging with users, building relationships, and creating opportunities for collaboration and knowledge sharing.

Build, lead, and managed events for technology trends and also launch a strategy to boost community-led events across the globe

Facilitate discussions and foster a positive environment among developers.

Create and implement engagement strategies

Collect and analyze feedback: gather feedback from users and use it to inform the product roadmap, identify areas for improvement, and keep a pulse on user sentiment.

Act as a liaison between the community and the company

Monitor and report on community metrics related to user engagement, retention, and satisfaction, and use this data to inform decision-making.

MAR 2022 - FEB 2023

Developer Education Lead / Livepeer, NYC — United States

Write content and create graphics that represent Livepeer, Web3, and various initiatives.

Collaborated with the marketing team and manage the content calendar

Created a social media strategy and increase our social following

Created a social media strategy and increase our social following (from 20K to 35.4K in total with an average of 350K weekly impressions)

Created influencer strategies, scouted, and managed relationships with creators

Developed and tuned Livepeer's voice on social media

Ideated creative ways to educate various audiences on Livepeer and web3

Events planning and hackathons coordination

Assessed the effectiveness of social programs and iterative on strategies to more effectively engage audiences

Built, participated, and managed events during Solana Hacker Houses and ETHGlobal (hackathons) events in the US, Latin America, and Europe

Created metrics reports on campaigns and channel growth

Architectured & collaborated to build front-ends experiences from scratch from design prototypes, wireframes, and specifications.

Built documentation and markdown repositories documenting the technology's usage.

Worked very closely with the designer(s) on clarifying and providing bi-directional feedback on the designed wireframes, prototypes, and graphic assets both static and moving.

Created scalable processes regarding development, deployment and user testing.

Worked closely with the Design UX/UI & Growth team, a team composed by designers, developers, and content writers on building, improving, and maintaining the existing and upcoming organization and project websites.

APR 2021 - JAN 2022

Head of Community / Niftify, Europe

- Grow the community of NFT Creators on Telegram and Twitter. Identify the most sought-after skills, and develop creative approaches to efficiently recruit top talents.
- Host online and offline community events, empowering people to create content, organize events, and advocate on Niftify's behalf.
- Meet and onboard new Partners, give them an amazing experience and the best tools and advice to connect to the NFT Marketplace
- Reporting to the CMO on a regular basis, on Community sentiment, Community business requests, and agreed-on KPIs.
- Liaising with the business on Community sentiment and acting as a 'sounding board' for future business decisions
- Overseeing the seeding of ideas and research for the business and collating feedback through the Community's Community Managers.
- At a strategic level, I acted as the Community interface with Marketing, Social Media, R&D, Public

Relations, etc.

- Receives guidance from the CMO to set the direction of the Community for the Community Managers
- Manage a team of Community Managers. Which included mentoring, assessment, and overseeing Community Manager administration tasks.

JUN 2019 - JAN 2022

Front-end Developer / Wavio, New York

Side Project

Designed, scoped, and estimated complex applications at the feature level.

Built applications and services that power new products interacting with Solana and Ethereum blockchains.

Envisioned and developed features to help build new applications.

Collaborated with the team and cross-functional partners on all aspects of product development.

Identified and advocated for team-wide areas of improvement and best practices.

Mentored team members to refined their technical and architectural skills.

Phovi Corp platform in Europe focused on IRL events.

JUL 2019 - APR 2021

Content Creator & Gear Guide / Moment, New York

Content Creator

Photos. Videos. Bringing Original Content to Original Businesses. Creative, meticulous, passionate, and savvy self-starter. Always adaptable and proactive.

Customer Service Responsiveness, friendliness, and empathy to solve problems and help creators. Clearing Help Scout and email support queues has been important.

FEB 2019 - MAY 2020

Co-Founder and CMO/ Pickey, New York City - NY

Side Project

On-demand photographer service — Mobile SaaS focused on Content Creation.

Pickey was a platform where those who create and deliver content can connect directly with clients.

In cities where Pickey is available, you can use the mobile app to request and book a photo and video session.

Development of a winning Social Media and Marketing Strategy for clients using industry best practices, understanding and aiming at the client's goals.

Content Creation in different locations for different platforms.

Social Profile Optimization (interaction with customers and potential ones)

Worked 1-1 with Content Partners

Built highly engaged social media following for my clients across Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and relevant social channels.

AUG 2018 - FEB 2020

Content Strategist/ Reebok CrossFit, New York City - NY

Orchestrated digital content strategies across all online platforms.

Drove traffic and engagement that translates to sales and brand promotion.

Managed content marketing budget.

Measured the results of marketing activity to inform future marketing campaigns.

Managed a team of writers, illustrators, and data analysts.

Education

2018 - 2019

Back-end, Front-end, and Mobile Development / Rocketseat

AUG 2018

Graphic Design / Shillington Education - New York City

Graduated on this Nano Degree with High Scores, was a fast learner and very proactive to question and understand more of the languages. HTML, Java and Python.

2019

Digital Marketing Immersion / General Assembly - Toronto

Nano Degree Programming / Udacity

Graduated on this Nano Degree with High Scores, was a fast learner and very proactive to question and understand more of the languages. HTML, Java and Python.

MAY 2018

Software Engineering / UniCEUB, Brazil

Product Series

- Business factors that surround product, business models, KPI tracking and product management for startups and enterprises.
- User Experience, bridge physical and digital experiences and develop data-driven.

Projects

- NoSQL databases and gained a better understanding of working with databases at scale.
- Front-end Frameworks to develop advanced HTML & CSS skills.

Introduction to Programming

- HTML
- Java
- Python

OCTOBER 2017

Nano Degree Digital Marketing / Udacity

Created Projects and models of Digital Advertisements, improved my skills on Facebook Ads and gained real world experience on advertising on Social Media by running campaigns on major Marketing platforms. Got rigorous project reviews and insights to apply on future campaigns.

Certificates

2022 2020

React / SheCodes Customer Success / RD University

2022 2020

Javascript / SheCodes UX Design / Georgia Institute of Technology

2022 2019

HTML, CSS / SheCodes Adobe Creative Cloud / AVMakers

2020 2018

Gamification Level 1 Course / Engagement Alliance Inbound Marketing / Hubspot

2020 2018

Swift Level 2 / Cambridge Certification Authority Social Media Certification / Hubspot

Swift Level 1 / Cambridge Certification Authority

2020 Photoshop Professional Treatment / MXCursos

2016